Michael Cuddihy Papers and Ironwood Press Records, 1932-2000 (bulk 1949-1988)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Michael Cuddihy Papers and Ironwood Press Records,
1932-2000
(bulk 1949-1988)
MS 358
Cuddihy, Michael
This collection consists of the personal papers, correspondence, drafts of his unpublished manuscript entitled Man on a Seesaw, photographs and poems of Michael Cuddihy 1932-2000. The records of the Ironwood Press and Ironwood magazine consists of contributor’s draft manuscripts of poetry, correspondence, chapbooks and select office files.
11.25 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://www.library.arizona.edu/speccoll
Restrictions
The fellowship application material in Series V, box 23, folder 6 are restricted until 2035.
Biographical Note
Michael Cuddihy was born in 1932 in New York City. His family was steeped in literature and publishing; his grandfather and father headed the publishing firm Funk and Wagnalls.
Cuddihy was 19 and a student at Notre Dame University when he was stricken with respiratory polio on Labor Day 1951. For nine months, he lived in an iron lung, after which he shifted to a rocking bed. Eventually, he used a wheelchair and was able to walk with assistance..
Cuddihy resumed his education in the fall of 1953 at Columbia University. In 1956 he moved to Tucson, Arizona, and continued his studies at the University of Arizona. Cuddihy graduated in 1959 with a B.A. degree in History. Throughout the 1960s, Cuddihy worked as a translator and attended graduate classes in American and European history at the University of Arizona. In 1966 he dropped out of graduate school to devote himself to his translating work and published an English version of Jacques Maritain’s The Peasant of Garonne (1967). While in Tucson, Cuddihy discovered his love for poetry, and wrote: “I was hungry for personal experience, anxious to get close to my feelings. Poetry might be a way. I began writings, spending hours with poetry, or alone in the desert or along dry riverbeds listening...” He began reading poetry journals and submitting work to journals; six poems were accepted by Kayak, a magazine known to publish new poets.
In 1971, Cuddihy attended a summer workshop at Cornell given by his second cousin’s husband, poet William Mathews, and it was there the idea for his poetry magazine Ironwood was born. The name for the magazine was chosen both for the symbolic and physical qualities of the ironwood tree. In Try Ironwood he wrote that while reading over his poems, he ”… came to realize, rooted as he was in a wheelchair, how deeply he felt drawn to trees, themselves deeply rooted yet reaching well into the sky.” It seemed an apt metaphor for a poet. Ironwood magazine was published from 1972-1988, and the Ironwood Press published 14 chapbooks.
In 1979, Cuddihy married Mary Cusick, the sister of his college roommate at Norte Dame University. Mary, a poet, had flown to Tucson to assist with the magazine and became the business manager for Ironwood. Mary and Michael spent their summers in northern California where they were able to mingle with poets, and developed close relationships with George and Mary Oppen and Czelaw Milosz, among others. In 1983, Cuddihy was one of the founders of the ongoing Tucson Poetry Festival. On July 13, 2000 Michael Cuddihy died at his home in Tucson from complications of pneumonia.
Historical Note
Ironwood magazine was founded in Tucson, Arizona, in 1972 by Michael Cuddihy. It was projected as a bi-annual collection of poetry with occasional reviews and essays, although the number of prose works increased as the magazine became more established.Ironwood I magazine quickly became known in the poetry world and attracted such names as Diane Wakoski, Philip Booth and Alberto Rios, and received numerous state and federal grants. Many of the poems that were printed in Ironwood magazine were unsolicited. Poets eagerly submitted work for the final issue of Ironwood(no. 32/33, Spring/Fall 1988). Michael Cuddihy was proud of his accomplishments and the influence of his magazine in the literary world.
Ironwood published a number of special issues devoted to the work of a single poet. Issues of note highlighted the works of George Oppen (no. 5 and no. 26), James Wright (no.10), Czelaw Milosz (no.18, which was published prior to his winning the Nobel Prize), and Tomas Transtromer (no.13). Ironwood (no. 5), the first special issue, included seven of George Oppen’s poems, including the long poem The Book of Job, and an interview with him by David Gitin. These were complemented by a memoir from Oppen’s wife, Mary, and appreciations by Charles Tomilinson, Diane Wakoski, Bruce Andrews, Rachel Blau DuPlessis and Theodore Enslin. Memoirs and essays from Oppen’s fellow “objectivists,” Carl Rakosi and Charles Reznikoff, rounded out the issue.
The diverse range of Ironwood’s special issues focused on aspects of poetry or literary criticism, including (no. 7/8), with a section on Ten Young Tucson Poets; (no. 17), Chinese Poetry Symposium; (no. 20) Language Poets; and (no. 24) Poetics. Ironwood (no. 17), titled Chinese Poetry and the American Imagination featured essays and criticism by Robert Bly, Gary Snyder, Jonathan Chavez, Stanly Kunitz, James Wright, Kenneth Rexroth and others in a "symposium” format along with translations of selected Chinese poets. Ironwood (no. 20) was a dual issue featuring the works of Hilda Morley and a section titled “Realism and Anthology of Language Poets,” edited by Ron Silliman. The issue provided an introduction to the influential West Coast-based movement and its strong national participants.
Slight in appearance, Ironwood aimed to publish younger and lesser-known poets, several of whom were published for the first time in Ironwood. One of Michael Cuddihy's objectives as editor was to provide a wider publications venue for women poets. In the first four issues of the journal, only 23 of 138 contributors were women; it was not until Ironwood 12 that women comprised half of the contributors. Another defining feature of Ironwood was its regular inclusion of work in translation. Ironwood 1 had inaugurated this feature by including poetry by Jean Follain in translations by William Matthews and Mary Feeny. Other poets presented in translation included Pablo Neruda, Antonio Muchado, Paul Eluard, Rainer Maria Rilke, Rene Char, and Rafael Alberti.
Michal Cuddihy ceased publication of Ironwood magazine in 1988 because, he said “…it had become increasingly difficult to handle the endless flow of manuscripts with the kind of care and attention they deserve and that good editing requires.”
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 6 series
Series I: Biographical information for Michael Cuddihy and historical information for Ironwood Press, 1932-2000
Series II: Correspondence, 1949-2000
Series III: Ironwood Prouduction Files, 1972-1988
Series IV: Chapbooks, 1972-1981
Series V: Ironwood Press office files, 1972-1995
Series VI: Publications relating to Michael Cuddihy
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of the personal papers and poems of Michael Cuddihy and the records of the Ironwood Press, including office and production materials for the literary magazine Ironwood. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence between Cuddihy and contributors to Ironwood. The contributors are 20th century poets, including Kenneth Rexroth, Charles Simic, Czeslaw Milosz, Will Inman, Gary Snyder, David Ignatow, George Oppen and Diane Wakoski. The Ironwood productions files consist of typescripts, corrected typescripts, and when available, original cover artwork. The last series of this collection contains the writings of Michael Cuddihy, including seven drafts of his unpublished autobiographical manuscript entitled Man on a Seesaw.
Access Terms
Cuddihy, Michael, 1932-2000.
Poetry -- Publishing -- United States -- History -- 20th century.
Ironwood Press--Archives.
American poetry--20th century.
Small presses – Arizona
Small presses – United States
Wakoski,Diane--Correspondence.
Rexroth, Kenneth, 1905-1982--Correspondence.
Simic, Charles, 1938- --Corespondence.
Miłosz, Czesław--Coreespondence.
Oppen, George--Corespondence.
Stanford, Frank, 1948-1978--Correspondence.
Snyder, Gary--Correspondence.
DuPlessis, Rachel Blau--Correspondence
Container List
- Series I: Biographical Information, 1940s-2000
  - List of Cuddihy’s published writings, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ironwood back issue list and Chapbook series list, 1972-1988 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Personal material, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, [1930's-1992] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Papers Michael Cuddihy and family, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publicity Michael Cuddihy and Ironwood Press, 1972-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - College notebooks and papers, 1949-1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - College papers from class at City College of New York, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hotel Accommodations, Polio, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1952-2000
  This series contains mostly correspondence with contributors but there are letters from publishers and the extended Cuhhidy family. He prepared several standardized responses that would be sent to contributors whose work he did not think merited a lengthy response. For contributors whose work he chose to accept or whose work he admired Cuddihy would jot a few notes on the contributor’s envelope for his assistants to type.
  The series contains both incoming and outgoing mail. There is a modest amount of outgoing correspondence. The majority of the series is arranged alphabetically by name of sender. Only the last folder of outgoing correspondence is arranged chronologically by year.
  - Subseries 1: Incoming from publishers and contributors., undated
    - A General, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Allen Family Tucson, 1967-1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Alma, Nasira, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Anderson, Cindy, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Andrews, Bruce, 1976-1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Anthony, Florence, 1973-1981 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Atlantic Monthly, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - B General (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Benedikt, Michael B., 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bloch, Chana, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bly, Robert and Carol, 1972-1987 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Booth, Philip, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bronk, William, 1976-1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Brodecky, Bill, 1962-1972 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Burnham, Philip and family, 1962-1978 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Burkhard, Michael, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Burns, Gerald, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - C General (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Carruth, Hayden, 1980-1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cieciurna Family Tucson, 1957-1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cunneen, Joe - Hold, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - D General (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Dahlen, Beverly, 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Davie, Donald, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Duncan, Robert, 1968-1983 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Duplessis, Rachel Blan, 1983-1987 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - E General (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Edson, Russell, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Ellingham, Lewis, 1983-1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Enslin, Theodore, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - F General (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Fauchereau, Serge, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Felling, Helen, 1978-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Finkelstein, Norman, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Fisher, David, 1981-1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Fraser, Kathleen, 1973-1988 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Frost, Carol, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - G General (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Gallagher, Tess, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Gander, Forrest, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Gardiner, Mary and Arthur, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Gigvene, Nancy, 1968-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Gilbert, Jack, 1980-1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Glück, Robert and Louise, 1978-1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Goslicki, Jan, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Graham, Jorie, 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Gregg, Linda, 1979-1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Griffin, John Howard, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Guest, Barbara, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - H General (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Haines, John, 1971-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Hall, Donald, 1972-1988 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Hampl, Patricia, 1977-1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hanna, Jeannette, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Hass, Robert, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Hejinian, Lyn, 1975,1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Heller, Michael, 1983-2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Hirschfield, Jane, 1983-2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Howe, Francis (Fanny,), 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Howe, Susan, 1974-1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Huggins, Marilyn, 1975-1986 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - I General (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Inmam, Will, 1967-1990 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - J General (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - K General (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Kaufman, Shirely, 1970-1985 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Kelly, Bright, 1984-1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Kinnell, Galway, 1973-1988 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Knipe, Edith, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Kouts, Barbara S., 1991-1996 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - L General (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Lane, Morton, 1960-1969 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Levertov (Goodman,) Denise, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Logan, John, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Lyons, Richard, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - M-Ma General (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Mc-Mu General (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Machau, Lorrane and Bill, 1960-1966 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Marlis, Stefanie, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Marshall, Mary, 1964-1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Matthews, Ella, 1977 – 1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Mathews, William, 1972-1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - McBride, Regina, 1985-1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - McCaffrey, Mariam G., 1962-1977 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - McCarthy, Patrick and Helen, 1963-1999 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - McDowell, Ellie and Fletch, 1962 -1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Meredith, William, 1961-1972 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Meyr, Andy, 1985-1993 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Milosz, Czeslaw, 1980-1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Mitchell, Donna, 1977-1987 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Mitchell, Susan, 1982-1988 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Moore, James, 1963-1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Morley, Hilda, 1942, 1978-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Mueller, Laura, 1983-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Murray, G.E., 1972-1973, 1986, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - N General (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Nameroff, Rochelle, 1963-1982 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Nelson, Nils, 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Nelson, Nils, 1980-1989 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Nelson, Peter, 1974-1980 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Nelson, Peter, 1980-1990 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - O General, 1980-1990 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Oldknow, Anthony, 1983-1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Olds, Sharon, 1980-1988 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Oppen, George, 1973-1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Oppen, Mary, 1974-1990 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - P General (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Perillo, Lucia, 1985-1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Petrosky, Anthony (Tony), 1973-1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Powers, Liz, 1981-1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Q General (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - R General (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Randall, Eilleen, 1965-1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Rios, Alberto, 1981-1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Rowan Tree Press, 1988-1991 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Rudman, Mark, 1981-1988 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Sa-Sh General (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Si-Sq General (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - St-Sy General (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Seymour, Carlton H., 1961-1976,1986 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Shaffer, William L. (Bill,), 1961-2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Sharpe, Tom, 1972-1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Silliman, Ron, 1982-1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Simic, Charles, 1975-1989 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Sloan, Greta, 1977-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Sloan, Maureen, 1976-1996 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Stanford, Frank (Dorothy mother, Ginny wife), 1973-1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Strickland, Stephanie, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - T General (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Taggart, John, 1975-1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Tracy, William, 1966-1967 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Transtromer, Thomas, 1976-1988 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Tremblay, Bill, 1974-1985 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Two Hands Bookstore, 1975-1978 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - U General (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - V General (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Valentine, Jean, 1981-2000 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - W General (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Waters, Michael, 1983-1989 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Williams, Charles, 1971-1987 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Wright, Carolyn, 1978-1988 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Wright, James and Annie, 1977-1982 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - General Y- Z (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified sender. First name only, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified sender, first name only, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified sender, first name only, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified sender, no name or illegible, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Subseries 2: Incoming correspondence, family., 1957-1995
    - Cuddihy, Ann (Eaton),sister, 1961-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Cuddihy, Mrs. Lester (Ann), mother, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Cuddihy, Herbert Lester Jr., brother, 1960-1964 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Cuddihy, Herbert Lester Jr., brother, 1965-1969 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Cuddihy, Herbert Lester Jr., brother, 1970-1990 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Cuddihy, Jane (McGuire), sister, 1960-1989 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Cuddihy, John Murray (Jack) and Heidi, brother and sister in-law, 1960-1990 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Cuddihy, Lester III, nephew, 1959-1969 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Cuddihy, Lester III, nephew, 1970-1972 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Cuddihy, Lester III, nephew, 1973-1974 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Cuddihy, Lester III, nephew, 1975-1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Cuddihy, Mary, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Cuddihy, Mickey, niece, 1960-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Cuddihy, Robert, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - McGuire family (Julia), 1961-1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous family members incoming correspondence, 1957-1970 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 3: Outgoing correspondence., 1957-1995
    - Family, 1961-1970 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - St. Thomas More Catholic Newman Center Tucson, Arizona Lectures Series, Michael Cuddihy, Chairman, 1962-1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 1961-1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - 1965-1966 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - 1967 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - 1968 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - 1969 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - 1972-1999 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Series III: Production Files, 1972-1988
  This series is arranged chronologically by issue. Some of the files consist of published and unpublished typescripts, corrected typescripts, and when available, original cover artwork. A complete set of additional production material, such as bluelines and page proofs, exist only for Ironwood 31/32, the final issue. The entire series of Ironwood is available in the Main library, Special Collections and the Poetry Center at the call number PS1 .I7. Of particular interest to researchers may be those manuscripts submitted for special issues such as Ironwood 18 Milosz, Ironwood 20 Hilda Morley Language Poets, and Ironwood 26 Dickinson - Spicer. For the Dickinson issue, Susan Howe, a recognized Dickinson scholar, submitted several versions of her manuscript each version representative of the close relationship of the poet and scholar to her material.
  - Subseries 1: Published issues of Ironwood.
    - Index of issues, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - nos. 1-4, February 1972-January 1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - nos. 5-6, no. 5 is the George Oppen Special Issue, February 1975-November 1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - no. 7/8 Special section on Charles Simic, December 1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - no. 9, April 1977 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - no. 10, James Wright Special Issue, December 1977 (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
    - no. 11, March 1978 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - nos.12-14, November 1978-November 1979 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - no. 15 - Linda Gregg / Ceaser Vallejo Special Issue, March 1980 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - no. 16, November 1980 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - no. 17, Chinese Poetry Symposium and Special feature on Frank Stanford, March 1981 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - no. 18, Oskar Milosz Special Issue, November 1981 (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
    - 10th Anniversary Issue, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - no. 20, Hilda Morley / Language Poets Special Issue, October 1982 (Box 16, Folder 2-5)
    - no. 20, Realism, October 1982 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - no. 21, March 1983 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - no. 22, Robert Duncan Special Issue, November 1983 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    - no. 23, April 1984 (Box 17, Folder 3-5)
    - no.24, Poetics Special Issue, December 1984 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - no. 24(2), Poetics Special Issue, December 1984 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - no. 25, April 1985 (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
    - no .25, Interview with Denis Johnson, Letters to the editor, April 1985 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - no. 26, Second George Oppen Special Issue, October 1985 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
    - no. 26, Second George Oppen Special Issue, October 1985 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    - no. 27 Beverly Dalan, April 1986 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - no. 28(1), Emily Dickinson / Jack Spicer Special Issue, December 1986 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - no. 28(2), Emily Dickinson / Jack Spicer Special Issue, December 1986 (Box 20, Folder 1-4)
    - no. 29, April 1987 (Box 20, Folder 5-7)
    - no. 30, 1987 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - no. 31/32, Final issue, Movember 1987 (Box 21, Folder 2-4)
  - Subseries 2: Unpublished Poems arranged alphabetically., undated
    - A General (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Anthony, Florence (Ai) (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - B General (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Bacon, Theresa (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Burkhard, Michael (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Burns, Gerald (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - C General (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - D General (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - E General (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - F General (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - G General (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Gregg, Linda (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - H General (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Johnson, Honor (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - K General (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - L General (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - M General (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Morley, Hilda (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - N General (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Orr, Gregory, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - P General (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - R General (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - S General (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - T General (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - V General (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - W General (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Zagajewski, Adam, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Unidentified manuscripts and fragments, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
- Series IV: Chapbooks, 1972-1988
  This series is arranged chronologically. It contains the manuscripts and production materials for the chapbooks published by the Ironwood Press. Although there were a total of fourteen Chapbooks published, only a few of the manuscripts remain intact. One copy of each chapbook is contained in these files, and additional copies are catalogued separately as part of the Special Collections book collection.
  - 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - A mile called Timothy, G.E. Murray.
    - Footholds, Thomas Johnson.
    - Waiting out the rain, Tony Petrosky.
    - 1976-1984 (type="folder">2)
    - Separate creatures, Steven Orlen.
    - Chicago, Nils Nelson.
    - Executioner, Bruce Weigl.
    - Breaking free, Del Marie Rogers.
    - A Hacksaw brightness, Lynn Strongin. Cover only.
    - Crib death, Frank Stanford.